Very good and welcome one more day to
beta tech for those of you who are new to
the channel here we talk about software and
technology and specifically in this series
We talked about design patterns, let's go
to explain one by one each pattern of
design seeing its utilities of
explaining them with examples if not yet
Do you know what a design pattern is?
I leave the beginning of the series here
above and in the description and if not yet
You are subscribed to beta take I think
now is a good time to do it
This way you will receive notifications about each
new video that will be uploaded and for the
so you can follow each moment
new pattern that's what we're going to do in this series
and the pattern that we are going to see in this
video is the factoring pattern that is therefore
that I have seen has been one of the patterns
most in demand since I announced that
I wanted to make this series
So to understand the usefulness of a
pattern like this I think the best is
that we encounter the problem of
face so let's do a little
exercise and let's get to work
develop a part of a video game
that I think you like quite a bit as in
throughout the video game the enemies are a
of the most important parts to have
different varieties of enemies gives you
funny
game and allows to surprise the player or
even increasing the difficulty of the
game adding more and more enemies
difficult as you progress
at the levels therefore in our
video game we end up having a set
of classes each class would be then
a type of enemy to give examples
We have for example the bumba class
cupa class and bu class
all these classes as they are enemies is
say logical entities of the game
entities that do something that moves
that interact with the player who
interact with the map would inherit from
the same class let's put the entity class
the entity class would be a class that
defines anything that has logic or
that has some interaction with the
This game allows us to apply
polymorphism therefore every time
we have to update the list of
game we can treat all the
entities equally following the
video game development and to do it
Even more interesting we want to avoid that
the player memorizes the location of
We want to surprise each type of enemy
You never know what enemies you are going to face
find below
somehow we have to generate
enemies randomly this
It means that at some point in our
code in some function we would have
some kind of logic to create our
enemies but how do we build ours
enemies we use new kumba new kuta no
we can instantiate an entity because we do not
it is no concrete class it is a class
abstract, let's say that in some way
we have to choose our enemies
we have to decide which medium to use in
this case and how we want to surprise the
player we have decided to do it in a way
random so we introduce one
function with some logic with numbers
random to select our
constructor decide what we call new
something we are creating an algorithm for
instance enemies this seems to work
and our players really like it
who enjoy watching how each time they
a different enemy comes the problem
It arises when we start receiving complaints
of players who want more difficulty
who want the game to be harder
want to see more challenges we would have several
options for example the option of
modify our current code
give our enemies more chances
stronger to appear but this
would affect all players by
same and we don't want to change it to
players who are already enjoying it
are happy with their random version
from the program this is where we start now
to see little things to see problems since
Somehow we want to encapsulate and
reuse the different strategies of
creation of enemies that we have
We want to encapsulate the strategies of
manufacturing of these enemies
This is where the application of the
pattern factor and the factor and would be the
responsible for maintaining logic
in charge of building enemies would be
a class that we can reuse and very
important we can use in a way
polymorphic and in the end it is the grace of
have this whole pattern from the start
In our case, for example, we could
have two factors one that we can
call random enemy factory and that
returns enemies completely
random and another that we could call
random difficult enemy factory that we
returns only the most powerful even
we could have extreme cases like
a bomb factory that gives us back
always bombs all the factors follow
the same
interface because they all inherit from
an abstraction that defines the method
we could call him a creator of enemies
treated from here to incorporate
a new mechanism for creating
enemies would be enough to create a new one
factory class that will inherit from it
interface and implementing that mechanism
in the create enemy method this is very
important and is what allows us
use polymorphism since each time
that we need to use something to
expose enemies we will use the
parent class of the factory so
we will be able to modify the implementations
concrete when and how we want
Now we want all games to be
parties we had a bumba factor and that
We all want enemies but from
we randomly pass the random enemy
factor and we have generalized the mechanism
from spawn near enemies to an interface
In general, in fact, we have no limit on what
what we can do from here
we can pass parameters to a factor and
for example passing percentages of each
enemy or for example make an invoice
to receive a minimum level as
parameter to choose enemies from a
level up
We have therefore created a
very powerful tool that allows us
make many changes to our game
and what is more important is so
general that does not affect any other
part of the code since all the
dependencies are between interfaces and
Basically this is the factor pattern and
There isn't much more if we look at the diagram
vl formal pattern we can see that it is
exactly what we have drawn with the
example of the video game we have the class
abstract products that would be ours
entity class and the complete class
product that would be our enemies
concretely the credit class would be the
father of all our chopped factors
with creed kreator it would be for example the
bomba factor is well random enemy factor
and we must try to avoid confusion
this pattern with the abstract pattern
factory and although similar they make things
different the pattern of abstracts
factory allows you to create different types
of objects related to each other
families of objects, that is to say a
abstract factor and does not have only one
creation method has several
we will go into more detail on this
pattern in another video in the series
worry to finish I hope you
I hope you liked it and that you understood
Why the factory pattern is useful and how
You can implement it yourself if
I continue like this please subscribe and give it
like at least in some way we can
give more visibility to this series and without
We'll see you much more in the next video.
bye